<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>David Uhden Collado's Blog</title>
    <link>./../blog.html</link>
    <description>Latest articles and updates from David Uhden Collado's blog.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>

    <item>
      <title>OpenBSD: A Robust and Secure Operating System for the Future</title>
      <link>./../articles/openbsd.html</link>
      <description>Since its inception, OpenBSD has stood out as a UNIX-like operating system
        based on 4.4BSD, known for its security as well as its minimalist design. This
        article explores its philosophy of security and simplicity, key security
        innovations, and the dedicated community behind it.</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>/articles/openbsd.html</guid>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The GPL: A Tool with Paradoxes in the World of Free Software</title>
      <link>./../articles/gpl.html</link>
      <description>This article analyzes the contradictions and side effects of the GPL,
        exploring how its restrictions can limit cooperation and freedom in the free
        software community.</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>./../articles/gpl.html</guid>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Rethinking the UNIX Philosophy: Beyond the Simplicity of Small Programs</title>
      <link>./../articles/unix.html</link>
      <description>The UNIX philosophy promotes building systems from small, specialized
        tools. This article delves into the essence of the UNIX philosophy, common
        misunderstandings in the age of microservices, and how its principles can be applied
        beyond the operating system.</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>/articles/unix.html</guid>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Reinventing Operating Systems: Lessons from OpenBSD and Beyond</title>
      <link>./../articles/systems.html</link>
      <description>This article examines the evolution of operating systems, contrasting the
        enterprise paradigm with the philosophies of OpenBSD and Apple. It discusses the
        impact of backward compatibility on innovation and security, and explores the
        potential for a more flexible balance in the future of computing.</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 10:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>/articles/systems.html</guid>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>